A Guide to the Luther Porter Jackson Papers, 1772-1960
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
- SERIES VII. MATERIAL WRITTEN BY LUTHER P. JACKSON, SR.
  - F. Unpublished Works
    - "Labor and Land Tenure among Negroes in Southern Agriculture, 1865-1915" 1934 (Box-folder 68:1727)
    - "Labor and Land Tenure among Negroes in Southern Agriculture, 1865-1890" (Abstract) (Box-folder 68:1728)
    - "The reminiscences of Isaac Jefferson" n.d. (Box-folder 68:1729)
    - "A Proposed Investigation of the States of the Negro Laborer in Ashoillc North Carolina school" (school paper) n.d. (Box-folder 68:1730)
    - "The Office of Escheator In England 1307-1337" (1933) (Box-folder 68:1731)
    - "Methods in History and Government" n.d. (Box-folder 68:1732)
    - "The Civil War and Reconstruction (Missing Endeavor)" n.d. (Box-folder 68:1733)
    - "Biography" (1922) (Box-folder 68:1734)
    - n.d. (Box-folder 68:)
    - "Richard Wright" (Box-folder 68:1735)
    - "The English Agriculture Laborer and The Land, 1815-1927" n.d. (Box-folder 68:1736)
    - "Bicameral Legislature" n.d. (Box-folder 68:1737)
    - "Puritanism" (1921) (Box-folder 68:1738)
    - "John Locke" (1921) (Box-folder 68:1739)
    - "The Labor Movement since the Civil War" (1922) (Box-folder 68:1740)
    - "Masters of Music through Beethoven" (1921) (Box-folder 68:1741)
    - "Agriculture in Virginia" (1870-1890) (Box-folder 68:1742)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 68:1743)
  - G. Books
    - Preface n.d. (Box-folder 69:1744)
    - "The Rise of The State Teachers Association" 1865-1890 (Box-folder 69:1745)
    - "Holding the Annual Meeting" 1890-1905 (Box-folder 69:1746)
    - "Facing the Crisis" 1905-1920 (Box-folder 69:1747)
    - "Serving All the Teachers of Virginia" 1920-1935 (Box-folder 69:1748)
    - "At the Crossroads" n.d. (Box-folder 69:1749)
    - "Virginia Negro Soldiers and Seamen in The Revolutionary War" 1944 (Box-folder 69:1750)
    - "Negro Office Holders in Virginia" 1865-1895 (Box-folder 69:1751)
    - An Analysis and Summary of Ground Covered in the Dissertation: "Negro Labor and Property Holding in Virginia, 1830-1860" n.d. (Box 70)
- SERIES VIII. MATERIAL WRITTEN BY OTHER MEMBERS OF THE FAMILY
  - A. Mrs. Luther P. Jackson
    - "The Gillfield Baptist Church Building Committee" 1953 (Box-folder 70:1752)
  - B. Luther P. Jackson, Jr.
    - "Seven Days In Heaven and Hell (for Boots)" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1753)
    - "The Eternal Comrade" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1754)
    - "Parlez Vow Francais" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1755)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1756)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1757)
    - "American Labor" 1947 (Box-folder 71:1758)
    - "The Affects That Religious Experiences, Theology, and Ecclesiastical Organizations have had on me" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1759)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1760)
    - "Lament for the Living" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1761)
    - "Troop Turn" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1762)
    - "My Eyes Have seen the Glory" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1763)
    - "Economic Observation for over time" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1764)
    - "Land of My Youth" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1765)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1766)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1767)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1768)
    - "Rumors of War" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1769)
    - "Hunger" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1770)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1771)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1772)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1773)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1774)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1775)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1776)
    - "The Eternal Comrade" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1777)
    - "Chants in the Light" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1778)
    - "What Happened Between Me and The Girl Who Used To Live on Freemont Street" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1779)
    - "With Malice Toward None" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1780)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1781)
    - "Over the Mountain" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1782)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1783)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1784)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1785)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1786)
    - "The Popular Media: Part I, The Mission of Black Newsmen" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1787)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1788)
    - "Zoroastianism" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1789)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1790)
    - "Our Home Forever" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1791)
    - "I Hear America Singing" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1792)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1793)
    - "Fertility" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1794)
    - Notes For Speech n.d. (Box-folder 71:1795)
    - "A Proposed Investing of the Status of the Negro Laborer In Asheville, North Carolina" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1796)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1797)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1798)
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1799)
  - C. Laura Francis (Jackson) Fulcher
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1800)
  - D. Edward Jackson
    - Untitled n.d. (Box-folder 71:1801)
    - "The Story of Abraham Lincoln" n.d. (Box-folder 71:1802)
- SERIES IX. AWARDS & GRADES
  - Award from the Va. State college a certificate of merit, for composing the college Alma Mater n.d. (Box 72)
  - Printed Award, from the N.A.A.C.P. October 2, 1948 (Box-folder 72:1803)
  - Printed Awards, from the Elks February 15, 1943 (Box-folder 72:)
  - Printed Awards, certificate from the Commonwealth of Virginia to Edward Frazer n.d. (Box-folder 72:1805)
  - Jackson 5-19-43 for never being absent or tardy May 19, 1943 (Box-folder 72:1806)
  - Grades, transcript of Luther P. Jackson July 23, 1917 (Box-folder 72:1807)
  - Grades, Laura Francis Jackson's grade and attendance report to parents; Grades, Laura Jackson's grades from Va. State College 2nd semester 1954-55 (Box-folder 72:1808)
  - Grades, Edward, F. Jackson's grades from D. Webster Davis High School Ettrick, Va. 1941-43 (Box-folder 72:1809)
  - Grades, Edward Jackson's, report card 1943-44 (Box-folder 72:1810)
  - Grades, Adjudicator's comment sheet vocal solo, for John Jackson n.d. (Box-folder 72:1811)
  - Grades, semester grade report for John Tevis Jackson, from Oberlin College 1954-55 (Box-folder 72:1812)
  - Grades, John Tevis Jackson's, student grade report from Va. State College 1954 (Box-folder 72:1813)
  - Grades, Luther P. Jackson Jr. report card from the fifth grade June 1934 (Box-folder 72:1814)
  - Printed citation, citation issued by Virginia Voters League, Incorporated to Dr. Luther Porter Jackson May 23, 1959 (Box-folder 72:1815)
  - Printed birth certificate, city of Chicago, Department of Health birth certificate n.d. (Box-folder 72:1816)
  - (Box-folder 72:)
- SERIES X. PRINTED
  - Printed A.S.N.L.H. certificate; certificates, meeting flyers, annual meeting programs n.d. (Box-folder 73:1817)
  - Printed community choir program; the second annual community "Sing" Jan. 30, 1920 (Box-folder 73:1818)
  - Printed community choir program; programs for the festival of Negro music 1938-39 (Box-folder 73:1819)
  - Printed emancipation celebration program; 83rd Anniversary of the Emancipation celebration; the 69th Annual celebration April 9, 1948; April 3, 1946 (Box-folder 73:1820)
  - Printed Flyers; Voting record on major domestic Issues of Harry Flood Byrd; Prince Edward Country Civic League n.d. (Box-folder 73:1821)
  - Printed N.A.A.C.P. Broadside; Flyers n.d. (Box-folder 73:1822)
  - Printed Petersburg Civic Association; pamphlets for learning a trade after school June 9, 1937 (Box-folder 73:1823)
  - Printed Petersburg Negro Business Association; Thank-you cards, business cards 1941-42 (Box-folder 73:1824)
  - Petersburg Negro Business League Skit; A nine page skit n.d. (Box-folder 73:1825)
  - Printed V.V.L/ Broadside; Flyers for the V.V.L. 1944-47 (Box-folder 73:1826)
  - Printed V.V.L./ Broadside; Flyers for poll tax, V. V. L. meetings etc. 1941-43 (Box-folder 73:1827)
  - Printed V.V.L./ Broadside; Flyers for meetings n.d. (Box-folder 73:1828)
  - Printed V.V.L. flyer; League of Negro Voters, 1938-39; requirements for voting, 1934; list of qualified voters 1936 1934, 1936, 1938-39 (Box-folder 73:1829)
  - Printed V.V.L. Program; 1st Union Baptist Church mass meeting, 1949; Fairfax County Colored Citizens Association 1949, n.d. (Box-folder 73:1830)
  - Newport News Teachers League Program 1933-34 (Box-folder 73:1830)
  - Curriculum of the High Schools of Chesterfield County Va. 1945-46 (Box-folder 73:1830)
  - Voting Institution Handbook Petersburg, Va. 1943 (Box-folder 73:1830)
  - Louisa County Improvement League 1950 (Box-folder 73:1830)
  - Va. Independent Voters League booklet n.d. (Box-folder 73:1830)
  - Newspaper article entitled "150 yr. of Business Progress Among Negroes of Petersburg" Oct. 27, 1940 (Box-folder 73:1830)
  - Membership certificate for the study of Negro Life and History Nov. 19, 1936 (Box-folder 73:1830)
  - Negro Life and History Celebration Flyer 1942 (Box-folder 73:1830)
  - Emancipation Celebration n.d. (Box-folder 73:1830)
- SERIES XI. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Mrs. L.P. Jackson n.d. (Box-folder 74:1831)
  - Mrs. L.P. Jackson and Friends n.d. (Box-folder 74:1832)
  - Luther P. Jackson Jr. n.d. (Box-folder 74:1833)
  - Mrs. Jackson (she's pregnant) n.d. (Box-folder 74:1834)
  - Mozart T. Frazer, holding Lee Jackson 1960 (Box-folder 74:1835)
  - Mrs. Luther P. Jackson, holding her grandchildren 1956 (Box-folder 74:1836)
  - Edward F. Jackson, and his wife and children 1958 (Box-folder 74:1837)
  - n.d. (Box-folder 74:)
  - Mr. L.P. Jackson & mother n.d. (Box-folder 74:1838)
  - Laura Jackson n.d. (Box-folder 74:1839)
  - John T. Jackson n.d. (Box-folder 74:1840)
  - Mrs. L.P. Jackson and friend n.d. (Box-folder 74:1841)
  - Mrs. L.P. Jackson and friend n.d. (Box-folder 74:1842)
  - Mrs. L.P. Jackson (she's pregnant) n.d. (Box-folder 74:1843)
  - At Va. State University the Jackson Family: Edward F. Jackson and wife, Mrs. Luther P. Jackson and daughter Laura, and son John Tevis Jackson 1953 (Box-folder 74:1844)
  - Luther P. Jackson Jr. and his sister Laura n.d. (Box-folder 74:1845)
  - The Jackson Family, Luther P. Jr., Edward, Laura, John n.d. (Box-folder 74:1846)
  - A negative of Delois (ligtfoot) Jackson Edwards wife n.d. (Box-folder 74:1847)
  - William Nash Stevens n.d. (Box-folder 75:1848)
  - M. Olivia Cumber n.d. (Box-folder 75:1849)
  - S.F. Daly n.d. (Box-folder 75:1850)
  - Geraldine Banks Foster n.d. (Box-folder 75:1851)
  - Royal Nickens n.d. (Box-folder 75:1852)
  - Royal Nickens n.d. (Box-folder 75:1853)
  - Ruth L. Mealy n.d. (Box-folder 75:1854)
  - Joseph Roane n.d. (Box-folder 75:1855)
  - Christopher Stevens n.d. (Box-folder 75:1856)
  - William N. Stevens n.d. (Box-folder 75:1857)
  - Mildred Brown Williams n.d. (Box-folder 75:1858)
  - William Stevens 1876 (Box-folder 75:1859)
  - V.B. Gaskin n.d. (Box-folder 75:1860)
  - Don Vincent Estill n.d. (Box-folder 75:1861)
  - Don Vincent Estill n.d. (Box-folder 75:1862)
  - Photo unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 75:1863)
  - Photo unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 75:1864)
  - Photo unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 75:1865)
  - Photo unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 75:1866)
  - Photo unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 75:1867)
  - Photo unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 75:1868)
  - Ross Hamilton Family (original) n.d. (Box-folder 75:1869)
  - Ross Hamilton Family (copy) n.d. (Box-folder 75:1870)
  - Daniel M. Morton (original) n.d. (Box-folder 75:1871)
  - Samuel P. Bolling 1819-1900 (Box-folder 75:1872)
  - J.W.E. Thomas (original) n.d. (Box-folder 75:1873)
  - J.W.E. Thomas (copy) n.d. (Box-folder 75:1874)
  - Photo unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 75:1875)
  - Photo unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 75:1876)
  - Daniel M. Martin (copy) n.d. (Box-folder 75:1878)
  - Luther Porter Jackson, Sr. n.d. (Box-folder 76:1879)
  - Community Choir Photograph n.d. (Box-folder 76:1880)
  - Luther P. Jackson, Jr. n.d. (Box-folder 76:1881)
  - Luther P. Jackson, Sr. & Group n.d. (Box-folder 76:1882)
  - Mrs. L.P. Jackson & Group n.d. (Box-folder 76:1883)
  - DeLios (Lightfoot) Jackson n.d. (Box-folder 76:1884)
  - Marie Jackson n.d. (Box-folder 76:1885)
  - P.T. Frazer n.d. (Box-folder 76:1886)
  - L.A. Black n.d. (Box-folder 76:1887)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 76:1888)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 76:1889)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 76:1890)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 76:1891)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 76:1892)
  - Printers Blocks used by Jackson for his publication n.d. (Box 77)
  - Printers Blocks used by Jackson for his publication n.d. (Box 78)
  - Printers Blocks used by Jackson for his publication n.d. (Box 79)
  - Printers Blocks used by Jackson for his publication n.d. (Box 80)
  - Contains, an off white scarf, cufflinks, tie pins, belt buckle, stamps, and graduation cap n.d. (Box 81)
  - Contains three appointment books, a phone books, date books, a napkin a baby book, a sketch book, baby records book about love photo book n.d. (Box 82)
  - Bridal book, 5 memorial records, a little notebook used as appointment books, and notes, bills, and reminders schedules books n. (Box 83)
  - Newspaper clippings/ articles n.d., 1948, 1950 (Box 85)
    This box contains articles about Negroes in the United States, race vote in Tampa, colored men's progressive club, Negro principal to stay as school integrates, a sample form of application for registration to vote in the state of Louisiana. A Virginia Statesman for April 21, 1950, the Southern Patriot, New Orleans, Louisiana, December 1948. "The Boswell Amendment: Reaction in Alabama," Virginias Journal and Guide April 22, 1950, the Progress Index.